<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: threex | Learning Three.js]]></title>
  <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/categories/threex/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-24T17:42:35+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://learningthreejs.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerome Etienne]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crazy Post Processing Color Effects To Change Your Game Ambiance With Threex.coloradjust Game Extension For Three.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2014/04/24/crazy-post-processing-color-effects-to-change-your-game-ambiance-with-threex-dot-coloradjust-game-extension-for-three-dot-js/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-24T13:47:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2014/04/24/crazy-post-processing-color-effects-to-change-your-game-ambiance-with-threex-dot-coloradjust-game-extension-for-three-dot-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://jeromeetienne.github.io/threex.coloradjust/examples/demo.html' target='_blank'><img class="right" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jeromeetienne/threex.coloradjust/master/examples/images/screenshot-threex-coloradjust-512x512.jpg" width="250" height="250"></a>
This is post is part of the <a href="/blog/categories/threexaday/">'one threex a day' challenge</a>.
This challenge is to publish every day one game extension for three.js!
One per day, every day and that for 2month!
In this post, we gonna talk about
<a href="http://www.threejsgames.com/extensions/#threex.coloradjust">threex.coloradjust</a>.
threex.coloradjust is a
<a href="http://www.threejsgames.com/extensions/">threex game extension for three.js</a>.
It provides a color adjustement in post processing.
It happens on the whole screen and changes every colors giving a whole new ambiance to your games.
It includes smooth transitions between each ambiance.
There are 22 ambiances going from 'sepia', to 'thermal', or 'radioactive'.
I highly recommend 'nightvision' if your game is about fps shooting at night!
It is very flexible, you can build your own ambiance with any image editing software.
It is ported from
<a href="http://webglsamples.googlecode.com/hg/color-adjust/color-adjust.html">color-adjust demo</a>
by
<a href="http://greggman.com/">greggman</a>.
Here is a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rfQ8rKGTVlg#t=25m03s">video</a>
where you can see greggman explaining the underlying technic.
It explains how to do 3d texture in webgl! :)</p>

<p><a href='http://jeromeetienne.github.io/threex.coloradjust/examples/demo.html' target='_blank'><input type="button" value='Try Threex.coloradjust Demo Now' /></a></p>

<p>To see the <a href="/blog/categories/threexaday/">other posts about one threex a day</a> and forget our moto!
<strong>"A THREEx extension a day, gets your game on its way!"</strong></p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/jhCKQqVIcG0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h1>Show Don't Tell</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://jeromeetienne.github.io/threex.coloradjust/examples/basic.html">examples/basic.html</a>
[<a href="https://github.com/jeromeetienne/threex.coloradjust/blob/master/examples/basic.html">view source</a>] :
It shows how to use the <code>THREEx.ColorAdjust.Renderer</code>.
It changes the color cube randomly every 3-seconds just to put some animations</li>
<li><a href="http://jeromeetienne.github.io/threex.coloradjust/examples/demo.html">examples/demo.html</a>
[<a href="https://github.com/jeromeetienne/threex.coloradjust/blob/master/examples/demo.html">view source</a>] :
It show an video with the adjusted colors.
You can play with it to get a better feeling of what this effect can do for you.</li>
</ul>


<iframe width="100%" height="480" src="http://jeromeetienne.github.io/threex.coloradjust/examples/demo.html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h1>How To Install It</h1>

<p>You can install it via script tag</p>

<p>```html</p>

<script src='threex.coloradjust.js'></script>


<p>```</p>

<p>Or you can install with <a href="http://bower.io/">bower</a>, as you wish.</p>

<p><code>bash
bower install threex.coloradjust
</code></p>

<h1>How To Use It</h1>

<p>It build the passes for the color effect.
It exposes <code>colorPass.colorPass</code> for a <code>THREE.EffectComposer</code> instance.</p>

<p>Create an instance</p>

<p><code>
var colorPasses = new THREEx.ColorAdjust.Passes();
</code></p>

<p>Everytime you render the scene, be sure to update it</p>

<p><code>
colorPasses.update(delta, now)      
</code></p>

<p>Then you add those passes to an <code>THREE.EffectComposer</code> like that</p>

<p><code>
colorPasses.addPassesTo(composer)
</code></p>

<h3>Tuning</h3>

<p>This module comes with a set of predefined <em>color cubes</em> : 22 of them to be exact.
You can set the color cube you want: one of the 22 already provided, or your own.
It default to <code>default</code>.
Here is the full list of available colors adjustement : default,
monochrome,
sepia,
saturated,
posterize,
inverse,
color-negative,
high-contrast-bw,
funky-contrast,
nightvision,
thermal,
black-white,
hue-plus-60,
hue-plus-180,
hue-minus-60,
red-to-cyan,
blues,
infrared,
radioactive,
goolgey,
bgy.</p>

<p><code>javascript
// set color adjustement to 'nightvision'
colorPasses.setColorCube('nightvision')
</code></p>

<p>There is a smooth linear transition between the old colorCube and the new colorCube.
You can tune the delay like this.</p>

<p><code>javascript
// set the transition delay to 2 seconds
colorPasses.delay   = 2;
</code></p>

<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7639554">Discuss this post on Hacker News.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One THREEx a Day Gets Your Game On Its Way! A Challenge!]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2014/04/22/one-threex-a-day-gets-your-game-on-its-way-a-challenge/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T17:51:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2014/04/22/one-threex-a-day-gets-your-game-on-its-way-a-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everybody! I’m working on a new project that I want to share with you. But first, let me start by telling you what inspired me to do it.</p>

<p>Last week, I read an interesting article written by John Resig called <a href="http://ejohn.org/blog/write-code-every-day/">Write code everyday</a>. He explains how he succeed in efficiently accomplishing his side projects. This article opened my eyes. It was like a revelation, a procedure that I just had to apply to my own work. An answer to the questions I had been asking myself: How could I be more efficient? How could I be more disciplined and improve my execution?</p>

<p>The tactic that Resig decided to practice to improve his productivity was quite simple: He tried working on his side projects a little everyday, for a delimited amount of time, and it worked! He didn’t feel like a failure when he didn't do enough "quality" work during the weekend anymore! He found a way to organize his schedule, do his work, while still devoting time to leisure activities. I find this amazingly intelligent!</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/CShTdamWAzg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Resig’s work inspired me. So, I wanna try to do something similar: I want to publish a three.js game extension every day! Yes I know, it’s a challenge! But I wanna see if Resig’s tactic helps me gain more discipline when publishing my code. The idea is to publish one every day of the week, from Monday to Friday, one per day for two months, except on the weekends, because well, one has to rest at some point :)</p>

<p>Ok, so you already know that I love three.js, a javascript 3D library that makes Webgl. Three.js is the new up and coming technology, it’s hot, cutting-edge, and it has been deployed worldwide. Well, now I would really love to help you write your own games with it! I think the best way to do this is by publishing one three.js game extension per day. I have an enormous amount of information, and code, to share with you. I just have to get it out there for you to see!</p>

<p>Three.js Game extensions will make the dream of developing your own 3d video game come true. My moto is <strong>“One threex per day, gets your game on it’s way!”</strong> I’ve got over <a href="http://www.threejsgames.com/extensions/">40 cool extensions</a> that could be used to facilitate the development of 3D games on the web. And I wanna share this knowledge with the world!</p>

<p><a href='http://jeromeetienne.github.io/stellar7/' target='_blank'><img class="right" src="http://learningthreejs.com/data/2014-04-22-one-threex-a-day-gets-your-game-on-its-way-a-challenge/images/stellar7-screenshot.png" width="444" height="250"></a>
Most of the three.js game extensions that I will publish support require.js and it would be very easy to add them to your own game. With these extensions you can actually learn to code 3D mini-games in less than an hour, like <a href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2014/01/10/flying-spaceship-minigame/">Flying Spaceships</a> or to create more detailed video games with a lot of cool post-processing effects, like <a href="http://jeromeetienne.github.io/stellar7/">Stellar7</a>. Just to give you an idea, I coded Stellar7 in only 2 weeks thanks to threex extensions! That's a record :)</p>

<p>The three.js game extensions will teach you real skills and tools to help you develop cool stuff on 3D. The best part is that you can reproduce everything you learn cause it’s all open source and available to anyone!</p>

<p>The Three.Js Games mission is to ignite the spark of genius creativity that every developer has.</p>

<p>I hope you enjoy it :)</p>

<p>That’s all folks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
