<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | Learning Three.js]]></title>
  <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-17T13:15:38+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://learningthreejs.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerome Etienne]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Three.js News #12: Creative demos of the week]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/08/17/learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-17T13:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/08/17/learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everybody,</p>

<p>This post is a special edition of Three.js News. We have decided to change the format a bit. We will continue publishing the most interesting and creative demos in web 3D. We will collect the ones that we have tweeted during the week and highlight each one. It's more of a Newsletter kind of style. Hope you like it :)</p>

<h3>Icosahedron Snake</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-17-learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/screenshots/icosahedron_snake.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-08-10 at 10 43 09" /></p>

<p>Fun and twisty three.js <a href="http://codepen.io/tdhooper/full/ZGPOQJ/">demo</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/tdhooper">Thomas Hooper</a> on Codepen.io. It's a spiral snake making its way in a funky pink background.</p>

<h3>Vortex Pair Warp</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-17-learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/screenshots/vortex_pair_warp.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-08-10 at 10 51 34" /></p>

<p>Generative net of cells from Turing pattern with gradient flow. It's got twin vortex mouse and cool shaders. The <a href="http://cake23.de/vortex-pair-warp.html">demo</a> is by <a href="https://twitter.com/flexi23">Felix Woitzel</a>.</p>

<h3>Harvest</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-17-learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/screenshots/harvest.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-08-14 at 14 22 35" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://www.loxodrome.io/Harvest/index.html">demo</a> is a 3d platform using three.js. Work in progress by <a href="https://twitter.com/JamesLMilner">James Milner</a>. Based on the three.js PointerLockControl example.</p>

<h3>BLCK4777</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-17-learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/screenshots/blck4777.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-08-14 at 14 47 46" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://www.p01.org/releases/BLCK4777/BLCK4777_safe.htm">demo</a> is all about realtime audio visual animations with "good'ole 2D canvas". Great project by <a href="https://twitter.com/p01">Mathieu 'p01' Henri</a>.</p>

<h3>Sneakers</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-17-learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/screenshots/sneakers.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-08-12 at 11 58 53" /></p>

<p><a href="http://travisirby.net/three-js-3d-webgl-experiment/">Sneakers</a> is one of <a href="https://twitter.com/travisirby">Travis Irby's</a> first experiments with webgl javascript framework three.js. It is interactive and it works on mobile too.</p>

<h3>Particle Shader</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-17-learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/screenshots/shader_particles.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-08-13 at 11 00 43" /></p>

<p>Shiny shader based <a href="http://pwambach.github.io/threejs-particle-shader/">particles</a> running with three.js and GLSL. Smooth and colourful demo by <a href="https://twitter.com/phil_osophie">Philipp Wambach</a>.</p>

<h3>The Thing From Limbo</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-17-learning-three-dot-js-news-number-12-creative-demos-of-the-week/screenshots/the_thing_from_limbo.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-08-13 at 11 09 20" /></p>

<p>Cool 3d <a href="http://thewebdesignerpro.com/glslshader.html">design</a> and animation by <a href="https://twitter.com/armychiu">Army Chiu</a> for the <a href="http://thewebdesignerpro.com/">WebDesignerPro</a>. It's got good use of shaders and shadow.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>Okay guys, that's all for this week. The demos featured here are all wonderful projects that deserve to be recognised and shared. So don't hesitate to check them out.</p>

<p>Stay tuned and see ya next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News # 11: Stay Tuned With Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/08/07/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T11:02:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/08/07/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is another edition of Three.js News. We have collected some original demos with skilful effects and lots of style. There is a high degree of talent displayed on these projects. In this episode, we will cycle through the daring climbs of the Tour de France. We will turn around decadent blue worlds, play with colourful Rubik's cube and take the new Renault Espace for a test run. We will also merge and morph with creative experiences and investigate fascinating generative compositions.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/jaVdFWl_PIo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>Metropolis</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-07-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/metropolis.jpg" alt="metropolis" /></p>

<p><a href="https://alexstockdale.com/metropolis/">Metropolis</a> is an impressive demo by <a href="https://twitter.com/ALIXPLOX">Alex Stockdale</a>. It is a spheric vision of an urban world in destruction, or construction, depending on how you see it. It has a decadent aspect to it, the light is like the shadow of a dream and there is a hazy bluish shade in the atmosphere. This project is not only interactive and skilful but it is also a great example of what we can do with three.js.</p>

<h3>The Climb of Alpe d'Huez</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-07-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/the_climb_alpe_huez.jpg" alt="the_climb_alpe_huez" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/sport/ng-interactive/2015/jul/23/tour-de-france-the-climb-of-alpe-dhuez-interactive">demo</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/amason">Andrew Mason</a>, Troy Griggs and Lawrence Ostlere, is a 3D representation of the Tour de France. We cycle a trail following the iconic Alpe d'huez climb. Step by step we learn about its history, about details of the trickiest passings and challenges to get to the summit....wonderful work by the talented devs at the guardian!</p>

<h3>Roobix</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-07-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/roobix.jpg" alt="roobix" /></p>

<p><a href="http://playcanv.as/p/V9B7k46n">Roobix</a> is a very fun game created by <a href="https://twitter.com/marquizzo">Marco del Valle</a> on <a href="https://playcanvas.com/">Play Canvas</a>. It is a Rubik's cube simulator with great animations. The rotations and puzzle combinations are extremely fun to play with. The cube is very reactive and the twinkling colours are part of the features that make this game unique.</p>

<h3>Renault Espace</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-07-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/renault_espace.jpg" alt="renault_espace" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://www.littleworkshop.fr/renaultespace/">demo</a> is an interactive prototype of the New Renault Space by <a href="https://twitter.com/glecollinet">Guillaume Collinet</a>. It is a webgl visualizer using real time 3d. You can go inside the car as if you were gonna take it out for a test drive. The interior and animations are life-like and will make you feel like you own it! You can visit Guillaume's <a href="http://www.littleworkshop.fr/">little workshop</a> for more stylish experiences.</p>

<h3>Omm Experience</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-07-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/omm_experience.jpg" alt="omm_experience" /></p>

<p><a href="http://ommexperience.com/">Omm Experience</a> shows us the fantastic world created by <a href="https://twitter.com/jhelf">Jean Helfenstein</a>. At first, there is an awesome lens flare effect with a halo of light glowing around a revolving asteroid. As the demo evolves, there are 3 chapters about creativity with great morphing and merging animations that transform and deform the object as if it was a ball of water.</p>

<h3>Gridiron</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-08-07-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-11-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/gridiron.jpg" alt="gridiron" /></p>

<p><a href="http://haptic-data.com/project/gridiron">Gridiron</a> is "an exploration of generative compositions based on vertical structures fighting for space" developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/hapticdata">Kyle Phillips</a>. We can see procedurally generated geometries that rain up and fill the screen. We can also modify their properties and play with the effects. It kind of reminds me of chemistry class.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this edition of Three.js News we saw the talent behind daring and challenging experiences like the Tour de France, behind life-like animations and reactive games like Rubik's cube. We floated through procedurally generated worlds and through spheric decadent visions of a city. We took a drive around our imagination and witnessed creativity in its abstract form.</p>

<p>Thanks for sharing. Stay tuned for more Three.js News and see you next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News #10: Stay Tuned With Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/24/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-24T13:28:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/24/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is about the 10th episode of Three.js News. We are very happy to share exceptional demos with you every week. In all the 3D experiences we have shared on previous episodes, we have witnessed talent, dedication and skill. Without so many creative projects we wouldn't have been able to continue with the news. So, to celebrate this 10th edition, we are going to travel through space, time and even dimensions.</p>

<p>In this episode, we will explore other worlds and make musical journeys across decades and light years. We will wonder around the Parisian metro in a different light and be amazed by the simple beauty of land and stone. We will interact with the futuristic and be repelled by the terrestrial. We will learn to safeguard and preserve our cultural heritage through online 3D, and finally, take a walk through the magical woods of the imagination.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/633x6HwnGPE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>Metropolitan IO</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/metropolitan_io.jpg" alt="metropolitan_io" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://metropolitain.io/">project</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/dataveyes/">Dataveyes</a> was made to represent the metro network of the Parisian underground. It is a Webgl data visualisation experience. It gives commuters information about the metro system, like journey times and people touching in at each station. It is dynamic and interactive. <a href="http://dataveyes.com/?em_x=22#!/en">Dataveyes' mission</a> is to transform human data into the best user experiences.</p>

<h3>I Want To See Other Worlds</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/i_want_to_see_other_worlds.jpg" alt="i_want_to_see_other_worlds" /></p>

<p><a href="http://primitive.be/prods/IWTSOW/">I want to see other worlds</a> by <a href="http://primitive.be/">Primitive</a>. Have you ever dreamed about traveling through space and time? If the answer is yes, then you are gonna love this demo. Primitive is a demo group with outstanding projects in their record. In this webgl demo you can see various elements floating through space. It is raw and pure at the same time. You will see transformations, visit fantastic universes and be driven through planets of the imagination</p>

<h3>Everything Is Fashion</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/everything_is_fashion.jpg" alt="everything_is_fashion" /></p>

<p><a href="http://stianj.com/fashion/">Everything is fashion</a> is a design and rhythmic demo created by <a href="http://www.pouet.net/prod.php?which=65978">Ninjadev</a>. It is colourful, fun and its got style. You feel as if you are travelling through time with the music. You go through decades, 80's, 90's...etc. The transitions are impressive and keep up with the beat, great and simple effects. It is both old-school and futuristic</p>

<h3>Light Year</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/lightyear.jpg" alt="lightyear" /></p>

<p><a href="http://lightyear.fm/">Lightyear</a> is a very cool experience developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/mikelacher">Mike Lacher</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/blackmika">Mika Chernov</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/lanewinfield">Brian Moore</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ilovechrisbaker">Chris Baker</a>. In this awesome demo you can hear how far music hits have travelled through Space. Music waves from radio broadcasts leave Earth at the speed of light. You can scroll to move away from Earth and you will hear songs that go way back ....even 100 light years.</p>

<h3>Bon Appetit</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/bon_appetit.jpg" alt="bon_appetit" /></p>

<p><a href="http://quasimondo.com/threejs/bon_appetit.html">Bon appetit</a> is a "creeping on your skin" demo by creative coder <a href="https://twitter.com/quasimondo">Mario Klingemann</a>. It will truly make you loose your appetite. It is a realistic and big slimy worm crawling on your screen. The texture is very cool and life-like. The slithering creature is in the form of a torus knot which makes it even more disturbing when it moves!</p>

<h3>Future Citizen</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/future_citizen.jpg" alt="future_citizen" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://ftrctzn.com/">demo</a> is a funky presentation of Future citizen, a studio making interactive web experiences for brands. It is creative and hypnotic. You can see the net of waves flow towards and against the letters. If you move your mouse around to trigger the effect, you will see that the interactions are pretty neat.</p>

<h3>Kessler Syndrome</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/kessler_syndrome.jpg" alt="kessler_syndrome" /></p>

<p><a href="https://www.chromeexperiments.com/experiment/kessler-syndrome">Kessler Syndrome</a> is a Chrome Experiment developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/wj_field">Will Field</a>. In this demo we can see the amounts of space trash that have been produced by space travel. The idea is to track some of that trash in real time. The red dots are points where the debris fly past each other at close range. In the bottom left we can fast forward to see all the potential future collisions of trash around Earth.</p>

<h3>Red Stone</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/red_stone.jpg" alt="red_stone" /></p>

<p><a href="http://potemkin.se/redstone/">Red Stone</a> is a beautifully polished demo made with <a href="http://goocreate.com/">Goo Create</a>. It was done by <a href="https://twitter.com/herrpotemkin">Magnus Östergren</a>, their creative director. The scene is like a desert with some subtle wildlife on it. It has wonderful lighting and shadow casting moving around the stone. It was made with an iphone 6. This is just an example of the cool things you can do with the Goo Create tool.</p>

<h3>Mount Rushmore</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/mount_rushmore.jpg" alt="mount_rushmore" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.cyark.org/projects/mount-rushmore-national-memorial/mount-rushmore">Mount Rushmore</a> is a 3D representation of the famous national memorial in the US South Dakota state. It was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/cyark">CyArk</a>, an organisation using digital technology to create and share 3D online libraries of the world's cultural heritage sites. Their mission is inspiring, they want to safeguard and preserve these sites to assure their existence for future generations. Visit their <a href="http://www.cyark.org/projects/">website</a> to learn more.</p>

<h3>Way to go</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-24-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-10-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/way_to_go.jpg" alt="way_to_go" /></p>

<p><a href="http://a-way-to-go.com/">Way to go</a> is an interactive experience created by <a href="https://twitter.com/vmorisset">Vincent Morisset</a> and his team: Philippe Lambert, Edouard Lanctot-Benoit and Caroline Robert. It is a magical walk in the woods which everybody can enjoy. It is fresh and fascinating with its wonderful animation, great old-school characters and 360° video. You can discover the world around you, interact with nature and explore your surroundings admiring the breathtaking effects.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this episode we travelled far far away, through some exceptional worlds. We experienced fashion extravaganza and music playing in distant light years from Earth. Our journey took us from underground Paris to primitive and futuristic worlds. We explored possible collisions and beautiful life-like scenes. We also protected our cultural heritage and discovered, in the woods, a magical way to go.</p>

<p>Thank you for your contributions. Keep them coming!
Stay tuned and see you next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News # 9: Stay Tuned With Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/17/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-17T13:17:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/17/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is part of the Three.js News series. If you have a taste for innovation and digital creativity in 3D, this series is for you. For this edition we have collected some very artistic demos. We will take a look at some unique projects. Everything from subversive and divergent experiences to particle libraries has a place in this post. We will play around with funny and endearing characters and explore objects around Earth's orbit. We will spin around colorful cities and visit impressive one man portfolio. All of these developers are taking creativity one step further.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/1Z-EEEggGFM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>Like to Death</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/like_to_death.jpg" alt="like_to_death" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://www.liketodeath.com/">demo</a> is a subversively intelligent project to show us the sometimes empty shell of social media 'likes'. It was created by <a href="http://www.geoffreylillemon.com/website/">Geoffrey Lillemon</a> and <a href="http://www.stooki.co.uk/">Stööki</a>, an independent design collective. How many times a day do we "like" something on the web? These clicks have a lot of power over us. In the demo you can see the figure of death and her demons on the middle. As more and more people like the project, it will get destroyed. Our "likes" will totally disintegrate the scene.</p>

<h3>Particulate.js</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/particulatejs.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-16 at 16 31 06" /></p>

<p><a href="http://particulatejs.org/">Particulate.js</a> is a JavaScript particle physics micro library. Developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/jpweeks/">Jay Weeks</a>, it is simple, fast and stable. The movement of the particles is amazing, you can see them flowing in and out and control them with your mouse. They come together in a compact cloud of matter.</p>

<h3>Sneeze the Dragon</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/sneeze_the_dragon.jpg" alt="sneeze_the_dragon" /></p>

<p>This creative, fun and very interactive <a href="http://codepen.io/Yakudoo/pen/yNjRRL">demo</a> was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/yakudoo">Yakudoo</a> on Codepen.io. Yakudoo is a very talented developer who truly has a gift when it comes to imagining fun demos like this one. The more you keep clicking the harder the dragon sneezes, be careful, that's fire he is breathing out!</p>

<h3>Blend4Web Player</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/blend4web.jpg" alt="blend4web" /></p>

<p>In this <a href="https://72b997d8354420ca04edc7734b26b346e696c605.googledrive.com/host/0B7Ss2VkVPiUHOE9SMjdlaHFQSmM">project</a> we can see a great real time cartoon model created by <a href="https://twitter.com/_Yadoob">Yadoob</a> for <a href="https://twitter.com/blend4web">Blend4Web</a>,  a tool for interactive 3D visualization on the internet. You can turn this funny Yoda like character around and look at the awesome shadows the model casts. Visit the Blend4Web <a href="https://www.blend4web.com/en/">website</a> to see all their different demos and designs.</p>

<h3>Christmas experiments</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/christmas_experiment.jpg" alt="christmas_experiment" /></p>

<p><a href="http://christmasexperiments.com/experiments/7">Christmas Experiments</a> is an advent calendar which features digital artists from the creative coding community and their web experiments each day leading up until Christmas. Some of the artists include <a href="https://twitter.com/michaeltheory">Michael Anthony</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/dmmn_">Damien Mortini</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/mattdesl">Matt DesLauriers</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/muroicci">Eiji Muroichi</a>. There many experiments and artists you can choose from. Each experience is magical, wonderful and it will make you jolly with Christmas spirit.</p>

<h3>My shards</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/my_shards.jpg" alt="my_shards" /></p>

<p><a href="http://myshards.com/?utm_content=buffer42e96&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">My shards</a> is an abstract experience developed by internet artist <a href="http://ezramiller.biz/">Ezra Miller</a>. It is diverse, divergent and very creative. Every time you click on it you will get a new texture on the screen. The change in color and design are awesome.</p>

<h3>Bruno Quintela's profile</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/bruno_quintela_portfolio.jpg" alt="bruno_quintela-portfolio" /></p>

<p>This is the impressive <a href="http://brunoquintela.com/">portfolio</a> of <a href="https://twitter.com/bruno_quintela">Bruno Quintela</a>. You can take a tour around his website and see the wonderful forms that contribute to the digital adventure. The WebGL aesthetics is amazing. It is polished and beautifully presented. A true masterpiece.</p>

<h3>Stuff in Space</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/stuff_in_space.jpg" alt="stuff_in_space" /></p>

<p><a href="http://stuffin.space/">Stuff in Space</a> is a sideral demo created by <a href="https://github.com/jeyoder">James Yoder</a>. It is a realtime 3d map of objects that are in Earth's orbit. You can explore  all the waves and transmissions surrounding our planet. The website updates daily with data from <a href="https://www.space-track.org/auth/login">space track</a> and uses <a href="https://github.com/shashwatak/satellite-js">satellite.js</a> a cool Javascript library to calculate satellite positions.</p>

<h3>Circular City</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-17-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-9-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/circular_city.jpg" alt="circular_city" /></p>

<p>This interactive <a href="http://codepen.io/Mombasa/pen/NqMMLX/">demo</a> was developed by <a href="http://codepen.io/Mombasa/">Mombasa</a> on Codepen.io. You can follow the movement of  a very colourful and revolving city. Nice way to build it using three.js You can see the streets and buildings closer to you as it moves around and uncovers itself. <a href="http://codepen.io/">Codepen.io</a> is a code editor in your browser, excellent for designers and developers to create wonderful projects.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this episode of the Three.js News series we saw demos bursting with artistic innovation and creativity. All developers featured here are true artists of the digital and 3D world. Their characters are memorable. Their ideas and profiles are designed to make a lasting impression in our minds. Their creations are aesthetic, useful, inspirational, filled with knowledge and skill. I hope you appreciate and enjoy their talents.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more Three.js News. See you next time</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News #8: Stay Tuned With Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/10/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-10T12:52:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/10/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is another post for Three.js News. In this eighth edition we are going to travel and dance with cubes, discover Swiss ground with points, and do some commuting with lines. We have a couple of educational viewers, one for asteroids and another, less space related but equally exact, for terrains. We will enjoy turning around with funky vertex and spinning helix. We will discover some beautiful models skillfully displayed in Three.js. We will also be able to measure and forecast happiness.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/5vPtKBlyQsA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>The Happy Forecast</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/the_happy_forecast.jpg" alt="the_happy_forecast" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.thehappyforecast.com/?utm_content=bufferdcbd0&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">The Happy Forecast</a> is a beautifully made and innovative social experiment. It was created by the team at <a href="https://twitter.com/weareclubhouse">Clubhouse</a>, an interactive design studio. In this project they measure happiness in every region and postcode of London. They did this with over a year social wellbeing research. Everything from public interactions to body language and audio factors are taken into account. You can visit their <a href="http://weareclubhouse.com/">website</a> to learn more about their cool projects</p>

<h3>Point Cloud Viewer</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/point_cloud_viewer.jpg" alt="point_cloud_viewer" /></p>

<p>The <a href="http://sitn.ne.ch/lidar/">point cloud viewer</a> experiment is amazing. It  measures the exactness of land, making an accurate replica of it. They have displayed the Swiss canton of Neufchatel. You can navigate through it, keeping above ground, increasing the moving speed, flying or changing controls. The ground will materialize before your eyes.</p>

<h3>Double Helix Spin</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/double_helix_spin.jpg" alt="double_helix_spin" /></p>

<p>This fun <a href="http://codepen.io/tdhooper/pen/NqyQQe">demo</a> was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/tdhooper">Thomas Hooper</a>. The helix have a predefined motion, their trajectory is spiral and never ending. You can see them entwined as snakes each with a different color, it is a very cool effect! You can see some of Thomas very artistic projects on his website <a href="http://www.stainlessvision.com/">stainless vision</a></p>

<h3>Fluuuu</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/fluuu.jpg" alt="fluuu" /></p>

<p><a href="http://labs.fluuu.id/iso2/">Fluuuu</a> is a fun and rythmic demo created by <a href="https://twitter.com/silviopaganini">Silvio Paganini</a>. Silvio is a very talented developer, we featured him in previous Three.js news. In this demo, you can see cubes dancing as if to a beat. They were inspired by Conway's game of life. You can change their size and color. Silvio did this for <a href="http://fluuu.id/">FLUUUID</a>, a London creative-tech collective that converges art and technology.</p>

<h3>Asteroid Model Viewer</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/asteroid_model_viewer.jpg" alt="asteroid_model_viewer" /></p>

<p>This educational <a href="https://www.chromeexperiments.com/experiment/asteroid-viewer">demo</a> was developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/iwebst">Ian Webster</a>. We featured his Ancient Earth project, which we loved, in previous episodes. Now Ian has created an asteroid viewer with lots of models to choose from. You can see various types of asteroids; a lot of research has been put into this demo. You can even see them in wireframe mode.</p>

<h3>Metrogram3D</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/metrogram_3d.jpg" alt="metrogram_3d" /></p>

<p><a href="https://www.chromeexperiments.com/experiment/metrogram3d">Metrogram3d</a> is a wildly interactive and creative demo by <a href="https://twitter.com/nulldesign">nulldesign</a>. It is a time lapse simulation of the Tokyo metro. You can see what is happening in the web of lines in real time. It makes you feel dizzy sometimes. We can realize the pace we are living at when we commute every morning...maybe we should slow down a bit!</p>

<h3>Cube Travelling</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/cube_travelling.jpg" alt="cube_travelling" /></p>

<p><a href="http://codepen.io/raurir/full/IAtie/">Cube Travelling</a> is a very cool interactive demo created by <a href="https://twitter.com/raurir">Rauri</a> on Codepen.io. The effect of the cubes or bars, depending on which was you see them, is fantastic. In this version, you can change the camera perspective and view. You can also toggle the colours. The motion is very fast and the effect is enthralling. In his funky vector <a href="http://www.funkyvector.com/javascript/#">website</a> you can check out all the demos Rauri has developed.</p>

<h3>Maya models converted to Three.js</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/maya_to_threejs.jpg" alt="maya_to_threejs" /></p>

<p>This <a href="https://alexstockdale.com/3D/">demo</a> was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/ALIXPLOX">Alex Stockdale</a>. You can see custom Maya models and materials beautifully and skillfully converted to Three.js. You can turn around the models set on the table, zoom in to see them more closely. There is also some great shadow casting in this demo. Alex is an interactive artist, we can see that in his <a href="https://alexstockdale.com/">portfolio</a> where he mixes code and creativity in his projects.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this edition of Three.js News we travelled with cubes, points and lines. We discovered how happiness can be measured and forecasted in a determined region. We enjoyed dancing, spinning and converting models to Three.js. All of these projects reflect researched studies, skills and creativity, and the elliptical never ending wonderment of web 3D.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
