<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | Learning Three.js]]></title>
  <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-10T13:14:18+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://learningthreejs.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerome Etienne]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News #8: Stay Tuned With Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/10/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-10T12:52:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/10/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is another post for Three.js News. In this eighth edition we are going to travel and dance with cubes, discover Swiss ground with points, and do some commuting with lines. We have a couple of educational viewers, one for asteroids and another, less space related but equally exact, for terrains. We will enjoy turning around with funky vertex and spinning helix. We will discover some beautiful models skillfully displayed in Three.js. We will also be able to measure and forecast happiness.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/5vPtKBlyQsA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>The Happy Forecast</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/the_happy_forecast.jpg" alt="the_happy_forecast" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.thehappyforecast.com/?utm_content=bufferdcbd0&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">The Happy Forecast</a> is a beautifully made and innovative social experiment. It was created by the team at <a href="https://twitter.com/weareclubhouse">Clubhouse</a>, an interactive design studio. In this project they measure happiness in every region and postcode of London. They did this with over a year social wellbeing research. Everything from public interactions to body language and audio factors are taken into account. You can visit their <a href="http://weareclubhouse.com/">website</a> to learn more about their cool projects</p>

<h3>Point Cloud Viewer</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/point_cloud_viewer.jpg" alt="point_cloud_viewer" /></p>

<p>The <a href="http://sitn.ne.ch/lidar/">point cloud viewer</a> experiment is amazing. It  measures the exactness of land, making an accurate replica of it. They have displayed the Swiss canton of Neufchatel. You can navigate through it, keeping above ground, increasing the moving speed, flying or changing controls. The ground will materialize before your eyes.</p>

<h3>Double Helix Spin</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/double_helix_spin.jpg" alt="double_helix_spin" /></p>

<p>This fun <a href="http://codepen.io/tdhooper/pen/NqyQQe">demo</a> was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/tdhooper">Thomas Hooper</a>. The helix have a predefined motion, their trajectory is spiral and never ending. You can see them entwined as snakes each with a different color, it is a very cool effect! You can see some of Thomas very artistic projects on his website <a href="http://www.stainlessvision.com/">stainless vision</a></p>

<h3>Fluuuu</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/fluuu.jpg" alt="fluuu" /></p>

<p><a href="http://labs.fluuu.id/iso2/">Fluuuu</a> is a fun and rythmic demo created by <a href="https://twitter.com/silviopaganini">Silvio Paganini</a>. Silvio is a very talented developer, we featured him in previous Three.js news. In this demo, you can see cubes dancing as if to a beat. They were inspired by Conway's game of life. You can change their size and color. Silvio did this for <a href="http://fluuu.id/">FLUUUID</a>, a London creative-tech collective that converges art and technology.</p>

<h3>Asteroid Model Viewer</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/asteroid_model_viewer.jpg" alt="asteroid_model_viewer" /></p>

<p>This educational <a href="https://www.chromeexperiments.com/experiment/asteroid-viewer">demo</a> was developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/iwebst">Ian Webster</a>. We featured his Ancient Earth project, which we loved, in previous episodes. Now Ian has created an asteroid viewer with lots of models to choose from. You can see various types of asteroids; a lot of research has been put into this demo. You can even see them in wireframe mode.</p>

<h3>Metrogram3D</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/metrogram_3d.jpg" alt="metrogram_3d" /></p>

<p><a href="https://www.chromeexperiments.com/experiment/metrogram3d">Metrogram3d</a> is a wildly interactive and creative demo by <a href="https://twitter.com/nulldesign">nulldesign</a>. It is a time lapse simulation of the Tokyo metro. You can see what is happening in the web of lines in real time. It makes you feel dizzy sometimes. We can realize the pace we are living at when we commute every morning...maybe we should slow down a bit!</p>

<h3>Cube Travelling</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/cube_travelling.jpg" alt="cube_travelling" /></p>

<p><a href="http://codepen.io/raurir/full/IAtie/">Cube Travelling</a> is a very cool interactive demo created by <a href="https://twitter.com/raurir">Rauri</a> on Codepen.io. The effect of the cubes or bars, depending on which was you see them, is fantastic. In this version, you can change the camera perspective and view. You can also toggle the colours. The motion is very fast and the effect is enthralling. In his funky vector <a href="http://www.funkyvector.com/javascript/#">website</a> you can check out all the demos Rauri has developed.</p>

<h3>Maya models converted to Three.js</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-10-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-8-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/maya_to_threejs.jpg" alt="maya_to_threejs" /></p>

<p>This <a href="https://alexstockdale.com/3D/">demo</a> was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/ALIXPLOX">Alex Stockdale</a>. You can see custom Maya models and materials beautifully and skillfully converted to Three.js. You can turn around the models set on the table, zoom in to see them more closely. There is also some great shadow casting in this demo. Alex is an interactive artist, we can see that in his <a href="https://alexstockdale.com/">portfolio</a> where he mixes code and creativity in his projects.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this edition of Three.js News we travelled with cubes, points and lines. We discovered how happiness can be measured and forecasted in a determined region. We enjoyed dancing, spinning and converting models to Three.js. All of these projects reflect researched studies, skills and creativity, and the elliptical never ending wonderment of web 3D.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News #7: Stay Tuned with Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/03/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-03T12:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/07/03/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is part of the Three.js News series. In this episode we will see some very cool editors, we can  share assets and create WebGL experiments with. They are useful, practical and easy to use; they are also a great way to start designing your own 3D models. We will take a look at some impressive demos with cute animals, multiple icons, shaders and crazy skills. All these projects are very fun to play with!</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/6AXl6gwwlCc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>Poonya</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/poonya.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 08 37 42" /></p>

<p><a href="http://community.poonya.com/156">Poonya</a> is an active community and a cool portal for sharing assets. That is, you will be able to share models, material, textures, animations and scripts with <a href="https://twitter.com/sea3dformat">SEA3D</a> Studio for web. An easy to use editor that allows you to create models and to share them with others. You have a wide range of tutorials to help you get started and discover all the functionalities. You can also take a look at all the projects, contributions from other developers.</p>

<h3>Chill de lion</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/chill_the_lion.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 39 39" /></p>

<p>Beautiful <a href="http://codepen.io/Yakudoo/pen/YXxmYR?utm_content=buffer71fab&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">demo</a> created by <a href="https://twitter.com/yakudoo">Yakudoo</a>. We saw paranoid birds in another three.js news. Now its time for the king of the jungle. You will see a very cute animation of a lion who is in desperate need of chillin' and refreshment. It must be a very warm summer day for him. By clicking you activate the ventilation and  when turning around with your mouse you make wind blow in every direction. The lion will definitely appreciate. He will actually smile.</p>

<h3>Holy Running Cow</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/holy_running_cow.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 40 36" /></p>

<p>This is another <a href="http://codepen.io/Yakudoo/pen/rVGraP">demo</a> done by Yakudoo. He really has a talent for creating fun animal characters! You can see  a very cute cow running around. When you press and drag the scene rotates, and the cow tries to pick up the pace.</p>

<h3>Mighty Fish</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/mighty_fish.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 41 24" /></p>

<p>We just love Yakudoo's demos. This one is called <a href="http://codepen.io/Yakudoo/pen/BNNGBq">Mighty Fish</a>. In it you will see a very determined fish, swimming with or against the current. Kind of Nemo's father when he couldn't find Nemo. You can move your mouse to change speed and direction and see how adorably funny it is.</p>

<h3>Many Icons Using Three.js</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/many_icons_using_threejs.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 42 27" /></p>

<p>Funky <a href="http://codepen.io/clockmaker/details/gpozrX/">demo</a> created by Yasunobu Ikeda in <a href="http://codepen.io/clockmaker/">codepen.io</a>. It shows various icons and letters that come together and turn into one, flowing in a replaying cycle. It changes color every time and it sometimes gives you the impression of being inside the Matrix. This demo was created using the Time Remap effect with Three.js and TweenMax. You can visit the Clock Maker <a href="http://clockmaker.jp/labs/">website</a> to see all Yasunobu's experiences in this interactive motion lab.</p>

<h3>Unstable Clock</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/unstable_clock.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 42 51" /></p>

<p>This one is a captivating <a href="http://freelance-html-developer.com/clock/">demo</a> and a Chrome Experiment developed by <a href="http://freelance-html-developer.com/">Tomasz Slawnikowski</a>, a freelance html developer. It measures time in an original frame. Every second is drawn according to the hour passing by. If you look a it for a while you will feel in a state of unreality, in a haze, hypnotic state. Even if it appears unstable, the clock is ticking!</p>

<h3>Crazy Skills</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/crazy_skills.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 43 42" /></p>

<p><a href="https://crazyskills.panasonic.com/en/">Crazy Skills</a> is a very cool project created by <a href="@panasonic_njr">Panasonic</a>. If you are a football fan you are definitely gonna enjoy it. It is an awesome presentation of football player <a href="@neymarjr">Neymar</a> incredible sport skills. Just in case you don't know him, Neymar is a recognised and adored Brazilian football player who plays for FC Barcelona and is captain of the Brazilian national team. He is very talented as you can see it in this motion museum dedicated to him.  There a a set of skills you can click on and see how Neymar's avatar plays on the field.</p>

<h3>Fiddling with shaders</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/fiddling_with_shaders.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 48 33" /></p>

<p>Very kaleidoscopic <a href="http://chrisirhc.github.io/_experiment-sand-webgl/push-field.html">experiment</a> created by <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisirhc">Chris Chua</a>. In this demo Chris plays around with shaders in WebGL to simulate force over an area. You can click and drag your mouse around to see how a trail is designed, go faster or slower. It almost resembles a small fish in the water.</p>

<h3>I'll be back</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-07-03-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-7-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/ill_be_back.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-07-03 at 11 45 27" /></p>

<p>Amazing <a href="https://c1.goote.ch/b9cca08d92a744e79a6772e13d624200.scene/">project</a> brought to us by the team at <a href="https://twitter.com/GooTechnologies">Goo Create</a>. Here is another cinematic and life like demo inspired by the last Terminator film. The effects and sound intensify the experience and the ambiance around is purely immersive. On their <a href="http://goocreate.com/">website</a> you can try out their great WebGL creation tool for ads, games and interactive experiences. Their editor is impressive by its simplicity and accessibility.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this episode of Three.js News we discovered some great ways to create 3D models and share assets. There are vast possibilities when using great editors and tools. We discovered letters and numbers that form together in time and space. We also played with fun and lovable characters and professional football skills. We hope that you will really enjoy experimenting with all these projects.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more Three.js News. See you next time</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News #6: Stay Tuned with Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/06/29/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-29T12:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/06/29/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is our new edition of Three.js News. In this episode we will be amazed by cinematographic experiences and awesome effects. Some of them will even give you goosebumps or make your hairs stand on end. We will explore physics engines, blockbuster movies coming soon, particles, portfolios. We will take a look at everything from a manga universe to a world of change. There is also a show off, a very special mention to a great experience that we found, combining 3d animation, motion capture and projection. These vivid experiences are unforgettable and all too real.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/mSJA2ZLWBfc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>Cardboard With Oimo</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/cardboard_with_oimo.jpg" alt="cardboard_with_oimo" /></p>

<p>This is a very fun and colourful <a href="http://puga.com.br/play/cardboard-oimo/">demo</a> created by <a href="https://twitter.com/marciopuga">Marcio Puga</a> using oimo.js. <a href="http://lo-th.github.io/Oimo.js/">Oimo</a> is a great physics engine developed by lo-th. In this demo you can see how the spheres change color and react when they touch each other and the surface around them. It's very cool and you also have a view for google cardboard.</p>

<h3>Insidious movie experience</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/insidious_movie_experience.jpg" alt="insidious_movie_experience" /></p>

<p>This awesome cinematographic <a href="http://www.insidious-movie.net/entertheroom/">experience</a> will make your hairs stand on end. The first two episodes of the Insidious movie saga really frightened me. I'm anxiously waiting for the new one. This demo is not reassuring. I think i'm gonna be even more scared! You explore the room around you and click on the hot spots, the story will develop with each click. The effects will have you screaming your heart out!</p>

<h3>1 Million Particles</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/1million_particles.jpg" alt="1million_particles" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://codepen.io/edankwan/pen/QbMxWp">demo</a> shows us a beautiful and subtile way of creating particles in codepen.io. Developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/edankwan">Edan Kwan</a> using curl noise and fbo on three.js. He produced a very professional and fascinating effect. You can change the color of the particles, the size, the speed.</p>

<h3>Aaron Meyers portfolio</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/aaron_meyers_portfolio.jpg" alt="aaron_meyers_portfolio" /></p>

<p>In his <a href="http://aaron-meyers.com/!/">portfolio</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/aarontweets">Aaron Meyers</a> creates a very cool environment. We can see his skills as a developer in this original homepage.Turn around in the room and by clicking on each TV screen you can explore the works he has done. You can also click on Aaron himself to know a bit more about him. This is hands down one of the most creative portfolios I have seen.</p>

<h3>Realize project</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/realize_project.jpg" alt="realize_project" /></p>

<p>If you liked the movie Ghost in the Shell you are going to love this <a href="http://www.realize-project.jp/">project</a> It is an homage made by true fans. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghost_in_the_Shell">Ghost in the Shell</a> is a manga by Masamune Shirow, there was also a movie made of it. This demo captures the universe of the manga pretty well. You can turn around and decide which icon to pop-up. There are very cool neon lights in the space, it gives it kind of a Tron aspect. You can also take a look at posts on VR and AI from other news-based sites.</p>

<h3>A world of change</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/a_world_of_change.jpg" alt="a_world_of_change" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://news-lab-trends-experiment.appspot.com/">demo</a> is part of <a href="https://www.google.com/trends/">Google Trends</a>. It is a great idea for social impact. Through google search you can click on topic (recycling, energy, water, natural environment, pollution) or a city, and see how those searches reflect the way the world thinks about climate change. You can discover what certain cities are doing about the environment. It is an eye opener and a great way to encourage sustainable development</p>

<h3>Terminator Genisys</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/terminator_genisys.jpg" alt="terminator_genisys" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.terminatorgenisysmovie.co.uk/insidelook/">Terminator Genisys</a> is another successful and  cinema based demo created my <a href="https://twitter.com/ParamountUK">Paramount Pictures</a>. You can get an amazing inside of the characters by rotating the camera to explore 3d models. You can also zoom in and click on hotspots for information and videos about the movie coming soon. It is very fun.</p>

<h3>Show Off "Le Petit Chef"</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-29-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-6-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/le_petit_chef.jpg" alt="le_petit_chef" /></p>

<p>Special mention to this great experience that we found. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yBJEP4lsRFY&amp;feature=youtu.be">Le Petit Chef</a> is a masterpiece created by the guys at <a href="http://www.skullmapping.com/">Skull Mapping</a>, <a href="http://www.filipsterckx.be/">Filip Sterckx</a> and <a href="http://www.antoon.be/">Antoon Verbeek</a>. They experimented with projection on a dinner table. Combining 3d animation and motion capture, a miniature chef turns your dish into a grill and cooks right in front of your astonished eyes. I wish I could book a place at this table! It is an awesome experience that I'm sure you will love.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>In this episode of Three.js News we have seen awesome projects. All very vivid and lifelike. Some movie related and some really scary, others more realistic and down to protecting earth. They all have their own universe. We experienced physics and particles, projection and motion capture. Regardless of how or by whom they were developed, all these experiences show us what is possible to create in the amazing universe of 3D.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News #5: Stay Tuned with Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/06/18/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-18T11:33:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/06/18/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post explores original demos with lots of knowledge. In this episode of Three.js News we will take a tour around 4D dimensions and creative subdivisions. We will also travel over webs of information and have fun with wildlife games. There is a lot of diversity in these projects, but one thing is for sure, they are all developed with the utmost skill and created for the maximum effect.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/oSDdZyM9cYU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>Paranoid vs. Shy Birds</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-18-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/paranoid_vs_shy_birds.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-17 at 11 00 12" /></p>

<p>This is a very fun <a href="http://codepen.io/Yakudoo/pen/LVyJXw">demo</a> created by <a href="https://twitter.com/yakudoo">Yakudoo</a> on CodePen. The bird characters are so cute. The one in the middle is the paranoid one. You can move his head around and see how he interacts with the small shy birds. The HTML, CSS and Javascript are visible on the scene.</p>

<h3>Threepark</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-18-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/threepark.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-17 at 11 00 12" /></p>

<p><a href="http://threepark.net/English">Threepark</a> is a cool editor developed by <a href="https://github.com/liguocn">liguocn</a>. Easy to understand and to use, great for artists and 3d lovers. You can create different models and designs. You even have a library of templates to use. Subdivide a model as many times as you like in the <a href="http://threepark.net/English/cagemodeling">cagemodeling</a> canvas. You can also store your models in the cloud and export them into 3d printing format. Great way to unleash your creativity.</p>

<h3>Parrot Hunt</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-18-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/parrot_hunt.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-17 at 11 00 12" /></p>

<p>Very funky retro <a href="http://parrothunt.nergal.se:8080/">game</a>, and also a Chrome Experiment, created by  Magnus Persson aka <a href="https://twitter.com/lallassu">nergal</a> . The idea is to shoot only the parrots, not the flamingos. You can move around and reload your rifle to keep shooting at your prey. Fortunately its not real hunting! You can get really serious and try to improve your score every time like I did! It's really enjoyable and it makes you feel like a great aim.</p>

<h3>Ntype</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-18-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/ntype.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-17 at 11 00 12" /></p>

<p><a href="http://ntype.blue/#speed=0.015707963267948967&amp;rotationPlanes=xw,xz,yw,yz,zw&amp;fpr=100&amp;string=NTYPE&amp;drawForms=true&amp;drawTrails=false">Ntype</a> is another Chrome Experiment demo developed by <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinzweerink">Kevin Zweerink</a>. It shows us a compelling and interesting way to explore 4D. The typography is extruded into the 4d dimension. You can change the parameters and settings and customise the rotation planes. You can even modify the trails that the letters leave behind them. There are also a lot of other designs to explore in Kevin's <a href="http://kevinzweerink.com/">homepage</a></p>

<h3>WikiGalaxy</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-18-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/wiki_galaxy.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-17 at 11 00 12" /></p>

<p><a href="http://wiki.polyfra.me/#">WikiGalaxy</a> is a beautiful and original demo created by <a href="https://twitter.com/WikiGalaxy">Owen Cornec</a>. This experiment takes us to a fantastic space that we actually already use everyday life. We can visualise Wikipedia as a galactic web of information. It's a marvellous world of knowledge. There is a map where you can fly over the planets, zoom and search. Wikipedia articles are stars, interests are nebulas. Have a good time learning! You can see more WebGL visualisations  in Owen's <a href="http://www.polyfra.me/">portfolio</a></p>

<h3>Multivers3D</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-18-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-5-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/multivers3d.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-17 at 11 00 12" /></p>

<p>This is the first <a href="https://multivers3d.fr/#/51184/Home.html">video game demo</a> released by the <a href="https://twitter.com/INF1N1T">multivers3d</a> team. It supports multi-users, cross platforms and it has zero install. This first episode is called Earth Creed. You are a honey bee and you need to harvest pollen and nectar from your environment. You have to use your judgement to equilibrate the balance of the ecosystem. This game will definitely make you love nature.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this post, we discovered some varied and original demos. We traveled through a space of information and explored 4D dimensions. We also played very funky games and designed 3D models with various subdivisions. The experience each of these demos give us is unique. Keep creating such wonderful projects.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more Three.js News. See you next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LearningThree.js News #4: Stay Tuned With Creative 3D Demos]]></title>
    <link href="http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/06/12/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-12T09:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://learningthreejs.com/blog/2015/06/12/learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post introduces another episode of Three.js News. In this edition we explore dynamic and constantly changing experiences. With the featured demos we will travel through time, discover new worlds and parallel universes. We will also get into fun and procedurally generated experiences that never repeat themselves twice; they are different every time, no matter how much you try them out. We will enjoy psychedelic effects and interactive experiments.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://learningthreejs.com//www.youtube.com/embed/YGGoZ6mB7yE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<h3>Ancient Earth</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/ancient_earth.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 14 45 41" /></p>

<p><a href="http://dinosaurpictures.org/ancient-earth/#0">Ancient Earth</a> is a very educational experiment found in the dinosaur pictures <a href="http://dinosaurpictures.org/">website</a>. It is a globe of how Earth used to look like, from 20 million to 600 million years ago. There is a list where you can choose any period on the evolution of our planet. For example, when multicellular life was first developed or when plants and flowers first appear... or even jump to dinosaur extinction! You can also remove clouds to see Earth's transformation and use the left and right keys to travel through time.</p>

<h3>Dennis</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/dennis.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 14 51 06" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.dennis.video/">Dennis</a> is a very colourful generative 3D experience produced by <a href="http://aaf.nyc/">Always &amp; Forever</a> computer entertainment and presented by NHX. It is a fun music video with music from popcorn_10. Frames are created in real time. Nothing is pre-rendered. Each scene is procedurally created every time you press play. You’ll never see the same video twice. Check out the <a href="http://www.dennis.video/#about">about</a> page to see how it was developed.</p>

<h3>Growing Tree</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/growing_tree.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 15 05 00" /></p>

<p>This <a href="http://gregtatum.com/poems/growth/#/1-seedling">demo</a> displays the beautiful and natural growth of a tree. It was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/TatumCreative">Greg Tatum</a>. You can check out his <a href="http://gregtatum.com/category/interactive/">blog</a> to see the other works and animations he has done. It starts out at the root, from seedling to tree with small incremental additions. It shows a dynamic growth of the 3D tree structure. Nice colours and lighting make it truly mesmerising.</p>

<h3>Another End Game</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/another_end_game.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 15 18 01" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.anotherend.com/">Another End</a> is a procedurally-generated game with an interesting story and a thread to follow. It was developed by Ryan Bottriell and his team. Inside the adventure, you are a player, created by Entity to reunite the 4 Glyphs which are essential to the world. You can have great powers; you can be Architect, a Protector, an Illusionist. Plus there are experimental versions to play it with Leap Motion and Occulus Rift. Follow them on <a href="https://twitter.com/anotherendgame">twitter</a> and take a look at all their developments.</p>

<h3>Simple Ball</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/simple_ball.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 15 29 21" /></p>

<p>Simple Ball is a traditional pinpall <a href="http://cwar.de/pinball/simpleball.html">game</a> for the web browser using Three.js. It a Chrome Experiment developed by <a href="http://cwar.de">Andreas Rominger</a>. It is very interactive and fun. You will have a very good time trying to keep the ball inside the game. The trick is to shake and tilt!</p>

<h3>Sanoran's Valley</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/sanorans_valley.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 15 33 27" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.sonorans-valley.com/">Sanoran's Valley</a> is an exceptional experience imagined by <a href="https://twitter.com/Samsyyyy">Samuel Honigstein</a>. It is a desert vision of the city inspired by Alberts Camus quote about the big city "being the desert we should seek to remedy life in society". Very philosophical! It has great shader effects and it actually uses Google Street View, so you can tap in any address you want and see how would it be like transformed into a desert. Check out Sam's <a href="http://samsy.ninja/">portfolio</a> to take a look at his other creations.</p>

<h3>Box Physics</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/box_physics.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 15 47 59" /></p>

<p><a href="http://labs.fluuu.id/box-physics/">Box Physics</a> is a very cool and creative demo. It was developed by interactive coder <a href="https://twitter.com/silviopaganini">Silvio Paganini</a>. We can see applied physics in the boxes using <a href="http://lo-th.github.io/Oimo.js/">oimo.js</a>. They react with a click of your mouse and they change color. There is also a very cool screen effect. You can visit Silvio's <a href="http://s2paganini.com/">website</a> to try out at all his experiments online.</p>

<h3>Magic Mirror</h3>

<p><img src="/data/2015-06-12-learningthree-dot-js-news-number-4-stay-tuned-with-creative-3d-demos/screenshots/magic_mirror.jpg" alt="screen shot 2015-06-11 at 15 55 23" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.alexeyrudenko.com/cc/js/030_triangles/">Magic Mirror</a> is another Chrome Experiment created by <a href="http://www.alexeyrudenko.com/">Alexey Roudenko</a>. It is an original psychedelic artwork demo. It is actually web camera triangulation, great for animation in a game. It is amazingly cool, you can use your webcam and see yourself in kind of a distorted reality. You can change the opacity and effect of the triangles and see the cool effect it has.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>In this blogpost we explored some very dynamic and exciting demos. We experienced ever-changing worlds where 3D is ever-present. We played some immersive games and enjoyed fun and altering animations. I hope you liked them as much as we did.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more Three.js News. See you next time</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
